Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ ahmedessamshelbaya (LinkedIn) twitter.com/AhmedShelbaya (Personal)

Top Skills

Mobile Communications
Customer Experience
Strategy

Ahmed Essam Shelbaya

CEO at Vodafone UK

London, England, United Kingdom

Summary

Proud to lead Vodafone in its home nation, keeping the UK connected. Commercially astute Chief Executive Officer with more than 17 years of industry leadership experience across Europe, The Middle East and Africa.

I have extensive experience in customer care, financial planning, and sales & marketing gained during my time as Vodafone Group Chief Commercial and Strategy Officer; CEO, Vodafone Europe Cluster; and CEO of Vodafone Egypt.

I have particular expertise in global brand and marketing strategy, big data and analytics and the delivery of new products and services, such as our new Consumer IoT range, Vodafone Smart Tech.

Looking forward to making Vodafone UK an even greater British tech success story.

Experience

Vodafone

17 years 10 months

CEO Vodafone UK

February 2021 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Group Chief Commercial Operations & Strategy Officer October 2018 - February 2021 (2 years 5 months)

CEO Europe Cluster September 2016 - September 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Chief Executive Officer
July 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 2 months)

Group Commercial Management Director April 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 3 months) Page 1 of 3 London, United Kingdom

Develop the Consumer Marketing strategic agenda, propositions and Go To Market

Develop and deploy Customer Value Management capabilities and best practice across markets aimed at value management, retention; CVM, Pricing and Prepay capability in an integrated approach

Define and work with markets on strategic pricing. Provide best practice guidance on propositions and services pricing. Define and Manage the wholesale pricing framework. Ensure consistency of execution across operating companies

Develop and roll out customer profitability models, ensuring optimisation of the use of A&R investments for better profitability. Managing New A&R Propositions

Define Group Commercial strategy on key topics and trends (Roaming, Over The Top [e.g. Skype, whatsapp], convergence) through working with different commercial areas and markets.

Regional Commercial Director - AMAP Africa, Middle East, Asia, Pacific Region

January 2012 - March 2013 (1 year 3 months)

London, United Kingdom

Work closely with operating countries commercial teams to develop and execute on commercial & brand strategy and specific commercial initiatives/ challenges

Lead for the Region on business development activity with small/medium targets and in support of the Regional CEO on major business cases

Proactively drive commercial best practice sharing across the region and/
or Europe; target and track execution of commercial practice with tangible business impact

Lead and support the execution of Group Commercial priorities across the region; identifying and coordinating Group resources and expertise to deliver specific initiatives

Lead for Group Commercial on the assessment and upgrade of commercial talent within the OpCos

Consumer Business Unit Director March 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 10 months)

Direct report to CEO, Responsible for Consumer Sales and Marketing as well as Marketing shared services

Customer Care Director

June 2007 - June 2010 (3 years 1 month)

Direct report to CEO

Managed more than 3000 employees in 5 Contact Centres and 43 Retail Stores.

Overall Responsible for Customer Service, Retail and Consumer Credit and Collections

Head of CRM October 2005 - May 2007 (1 year 8 months)

Education

IMD

· (2007 - 2007)

Henley Business School